(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.2",
"generated_at": "2026-06-21T01:11:53.908995",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、あ、あ、
Ah, ah, ah...
皆様、おーー！
Everyone, wooah!
いいね、コメント元気だね。
Great, you are so energetic in the comments!
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026、
Today is Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2026,
「Wind Trails」にご来場くださいまして、
thank you so much for coming to "Wind Trails"!
誠にありがとうございます！いぇーい！
Thank you very much! Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the show starting, I have some requests and info for you.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは、えー、電源切られると見れなくなって困るので、
During the show, if you turn off your cameras or smartphones, you won't be able to watch,
電源は切らず、写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき、
so keep them on, take tons of screenshots,
当配信のハッシュタグ、#風真いろは生誕ライブ2026 で
and please use our official hashtag, #風真いろは生誕ライブ2026...
SNSに大量に画像ポストしてください！
...to post tons of photos on social media!
目指せ、Xトレンド1位！よろしくお願いいたします！
Let's aim for #1 on X trends! Please help make it happen!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると充電なくなっちゃいそうなんで、
Ah, but taking so many photos might drain your battery,
スマホで見てる勢は、えー、充電しっかりしてくださいね。
so those watching on smartphones, make sure your phone is charged!
はい、そして、その2！
Alright, and number two!
激しく頭を振る、えー、激しくペンライトを振る、などはですね、
Violent headbanging or waving your penlight too hard...
あなた様のご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので、
...poses a danger of destroying your home.
あの、破壊されてもですね、こちらは責任一切負えませんので、
Even if it gets destroyed, we cannot take any responsibility...
あの、お気をつけください。ダメだよ、みんな。
...so please be careful! Don't do it, guys!
あ、そしてあと、もういっこ。その3。
Oh, and one more thing! Number three.
あの、今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてる奴は間に合わないからやめな。
If you're trying to make hayashi rice right now, you won't make it in time, so stop.
絶対間に合わないから。
You definitely won't make it in time.
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
Anyway, I hope you enjoy the show at your own pace while eating or drinking something!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、
Well then, the show is starting soon,
今しばらくお待ちください。
so please wait just a little longer.
最後まで見てねーー！
Make sure to watch until the very end!
風真いろは生誕ライブ 2026 行くよー！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026! Here we go!
いっせーのーで
Ready, set, go!
鳴り響いたスタートの合図
The start signal rang out
なぞった線で 結んだ世界
A world connected by lines that I traced
色付けていく
I'll start adding color
ここから
From here
物心つく頃 すでに此処にあった
It was already here when I became aware
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は
Memories that aren't mine...
夕陽とともに蘇る
...awaken with the setting sun
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
I took out the worn-out picture book
落書きの中に1つの答えを見つけた
And found one answer in the scribbles
自分の価値に 目を疑って
Doubting my own worth with my eyes
どこまでだって 堕ちていけるの
How far can I fall?
どこか遠くに 消えてしまいたい
I want to disappear somewhere far away
こんな世界じゃ僕はいらない
I don't need myself in a world like this
カウントダウンは
The countdown...
始まっているよ
...has already begun
“いっせーのー”で 声を上げて
Raise your voice at the signal of "Ready-go"
聴こえてくるんだ
I can hear it
自分の影の 長さに気づく
I notice the length of my own shadow
もうこんな時間だ
It's already this late
一等星が 顔を出した
A first-magnitude star showed its face
届きそうで 手を伸ばした
I stretched out my hand as if I could reach it
“次は僕についてきな”と
"Follow me next time," it said
どんな暗闇でも
No matter how dark it is
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
幕は上がりだした
The curtain began to rise
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
色付けていく ここから
I'll start adding color here
10年後の僕らは すれ違いばかりで
Ten years later, we are always passing each other by
幻想に想いを馳せては
I let my thoughts race in illusions
“戻れない”そう思い込んだ
Thinking, "I can't go back"
くたびれた心に 追い討ちを
Adding to my exhausted heart
あの頃と変わらない夕陽も
Even the setting sun, which hasn't changed since those days...
なんとも思わない
...I don't feel anything
自分を信じ 歩いていければ
If I could just believe in myself and keep walking
どこまでだって 昇れるのに
I could climb anywhere
カットを跨ぐ その空白に
In the blank space that spans the shots
大切なモノ 見落としている
I'm overlooking something important
見つけられないと 泣きわめく君へ
To you who cries and screams that you can't find it
“いっせーのー”で 声を上げて
Raise your voice at the signal of "Ready-go"
聴こえてくるんだ
I can hear it
自分の影の 長さに気づく
I notice the length of my own shadow
もうこんな時間だ
It's already this late
一等賞で 駆け抜ける君
You who run through as the first prize winner
くっついていただけの僕でも
Even I, who only stuck with you
君の前を 歩けるかな？
Can I walk in front of you?
こんな頼りない 僕でも
Even I, who am so unreliable
宝箱はホコリを かぶったまま
The treasure chest was covered in dust
なくした鍵は ずっと
The lost key was always...
君のポケットの中にあった
...in your pocket
散らばっていた全てが
Everything that was scattered
今ひとつに重なる
Is now overlapping into one
手を取り始めよう
Let's start taking hands
僕たちの物語
Our story
一度は いらないと思った
I thought I didn't need it once
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
Now I feel like I can hold my head high
愛おしくて
It's so dear
掛け声はいつも
The shout of encouragement is always...
“いっせーのー”で 声を上げて
Raise your voice at the signal of "Ready-go"
聴こえてくるんだ
I can hear it
自分の影の 長さに気づく
I notice the length of my own shadow
もうこんな時間だ
It's already this late
一等星が 顔を出した
A first-magnitude star showed its face
届きそうで 手を伸ばした
I stretched out my hand as if I could reach it
“次は僕についてきな”と
"Follow me next time," it said
どんな暗闇でも
No matter how dark it is
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
泣きじゃくった声で
With a tearful voice
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
笑う君が見えた
I saw you laughing
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
幕は上がりだした
The curtain began to rise
もういいかい？ もういいよ
Are you ready? Yes, it's okay
色付けていく ここから
I'll start adding color here
はい！ということで
Alright! And with that,
始まりましたー！
it has begun!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026...
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026...
スタート！みんな、こんばんはー！
Start! Good evening, everyone!
見えてるー？
Can you see me?
はい、ということで、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Alright, so here is today's hashtag!
こちらね、みんな、
Please use this one, everyone,
いっぱいポストして、いっぱいカッコいいとこ撮ってくださいね、頼むよ！
post a lot and take lots of cool screenshots! I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを
To let the world know
世の中に知らしめられるのは、
that Kazama Iroha is cool...
お前たち、お前たちだけなので、よろしくお願いします！
...is up to you guys! Only you can do it, so please help me out!
はい、そして今回のねライブ、タイトルがついております！
Yes, and this live concert has a title!
Wind Trails というね、
It's titled 'Wind Trails',
タイトルがついておりますが、
and as for this title,
ま、そのまんま訳して、結構お気づきの方も多かったんですが、
which, as many of you might have noticed from the literal translation,
風の軌跡というね、あの、意味を込めて付けさせていただき、
carries the meaning of 'Trails of the Wind'.
今回ライブ色々、頑張って考えさせていただきました！
I worked hard to plan various things for this live!
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
So, I hope you enjoy it until the very end!
そして、1曲目、かくれんぼ、歌わせていただきましたー！
And for the first song, I performed 'Kakurenbo'!
どうだったかなー？
How did you like it?
はい、そして今日、室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
Also, you probably thought today was an indoor live, right?
見てー！
Look!
曲中に、ドームが開きましたー！イェーイ！
During the song, the dome opened up! Yay!
すごーい！
Amazing!
やっぱね、なかなか現地ライブって、できてもさ、
After all, even when we do live concerts in person,
青空の下でなかなか歌うことってないので、
we rarely get to sing under the blue sky.
いつか、俺たちとお前たちの次元が交ざって、
Maybe one day, our dimensions will merge
空の下で歌えるような世界が来るかもしれないけど、
and we'll be able to sing under the real sky,
やってみたくてね、今回は、空の下で歌うっていうこの演出やらせていただきましたー！
but I really wanted to try it, so I went with this outdoor performance stage today!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
Isn't it great?
で、ステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで、
And the stage is super cool too!
今日ね、多分いっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、
You'll probably see it a lot today,
ゆっくり隅から隅まで
but feel free to check out every single corner,
アーカイブ勢もね、きっといると思うんで、
including those watching the archive later.
本当に色んな細部こだわってるんで、細かく見てくださいね！
We paid close attention to every detail, so please look closely!
ということで、あ、お水飲んでいいですかね？
With that said, oh, can I drink some water?
お水を、う、う、やめろ！俺の頭を、う、やめ、う、
Let me get some wa— Ah! Stop! My head— Hey, stop!
頭をいじくり回されて、ヘッドセットになりました。
They messed with my head, and now I have a headset on.
そして水が、水、用意してくれたんだよね？みんなに見える水。
And they prepared this water for me, right? Water that everyone can see.
うまい！
Delicious!
うますぎる！この、この振りはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うますぎる！
So good! I might get scolded for doing this pose, so I won't do it again, but it's so delicious!
うまいな。
So good.
これで、あと1時間やるか、そういうわけにもいかないんで、
Should we just do this for another hour? No, we can't do that.
じゃ、1回ね、お水ちょっとお返しして、
So, let me return the water first.
それじゃあ、水分補給もさせてもらって、息も整えたんでね。
Alright, now that I'm hydrated and caught my breath,
はい、次の曲、早速やっていきたいと思います！
let's move on to the next song right away!
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
「白線」
'Hakusen'
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky,
あの地平を超えて
beyond that horizon.
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
もっと！はい！はい！
More! Yes! Yes!
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で
It started with a little light expectation,
そのカケラそっとポケットしまって
gently slipping those fragments into my pocket.
屋上 遠い空の向こうを見てた
On the rooftop, I looked beyond the distant sky.
この足でどこに行けるかなって
Wondering where these feet of mine could take me,
わかってないけどわかってるんだ
I didn't know, yet I knew deep down.
白昼の淡い月に手をのばした
I reached my hand out to the pale moon in broad daylight.
かすれたエコー でも答えはもう
A faint echo, but the answer was already
はじめからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
something I had with me from the very start.
メイビー この想いは
Maybe this feeling...
マスビー 熱を増して
Must be growing hotter.
ほらね、飛べるんだ
See? I can fly.
もっと高く 高くまで はばたいてみたい
Higher and higher, I want to spread my wings.
今日に未来色の軌道描いて
Drawing a future-colored trajectory on today,
地平の先まで
to the edge of the horizon.
届かない歌はない 迷いはもうない
There is no song that cannot reach, there are no more doubts.
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない
Unshaken in any world or moment,
アイが在るから
because love is here.
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky,
不安と期待とアンビバレント
ambivalence of anxiety and anticipation.
でも声はもう気づいてる
But my voice has already realized,
もっと高く高く高く高く 飛んでいける
higher, higher, higher, higher, I can fly!
途切れ途切れの
Fragmented and broken...
紡いでたら「一途」に変わったよ
As I kept weaving, it turned into devotion.
あたりさわりない言葉じゃ
It's not something that harmless words...
覆いきれないほどのマイワールド
can completely cover in my world.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The owner of the voice that calls out tomorrow
他でもないこの心だ
is none other than this heart.
たった、見えていないその言葉も
Even those words that cannot be seen
「言葉」だと足りないだけ
are simply not enough as "words".
掴んだもの 落としたもの
Things I grasped, things I dropped...
転んだって立って 見えた視界から
Even if I fall, I stand up, and from the view I see...
ロックユー！解き放って
Rock you! Release it!
フォーユー！響きだして
For you! Start resounding!
景色変えてゆく
The scenery is changing.
まだ遠く遠くまで 広がった空に
In the sky spread out so far, far away,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんて ちっぽけだけど
this single step I finally take is tiny, but...
届かない場所へと続いていく
it continues toward a place beyond reach.
どんな風に雨に消えない 白線をかく
No matter the wind or rain, I'll draw a white line that won't fade.
もっと高く高くまで 羽ばたいていたい
Higher and higher, I want to keep flapping my wings.
そして彼方色で繋ぐ 地平で待ってて
Wait for me on the horizon, connected by distant colors.
もう願いに嘘はない ここがスキ！
There are no more lies in my wishes. I love it here!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く アイがあるから
Every world and every moment shines, because there is love.
今はただ想うこと言えばいい 「愛してるよ！！」
Now I just have to say what's on my mind: "I love you!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear blue sky.
不安と期待のアンビバレント
The ambivalence of anxiety and expectation.
でも君はもう気づいてる
But you already know.
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける！
We can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっと
More...
鏡よ教えて 私の証は
Mirror, mirror, tell me, where is the proof of my existence?
どこにあるのだろう
Where could it be?
分からない 分からないよ
I don't know, I just don't know.
周りと比べたってさ
Comparing myself to others...
虚しくなるだけ
only makes me feel empty.
あのノイズが
That noise...
涙に似た調べに 涙を奪う
steals my tears with a melody resembling them.
切り取った風景を 道しるべにしよう
Let's make this captured scenery our signpost.
そうだ
That's right.
傷ついた感情も 捨てていくなら
If we are going to cast away our wounded emotions...
そっと響くカンパネラ
The softly resounding Campanella...
新しい未来を感じてる
makes us feel a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょ
Even if we're scared, we have to move forward, right?
遠くまで
Far away...
もっと もっと
more, more...
届けこの祈りよ光となれ
reach out, this prayer, and turn into light!
もっと もっと
More, more...
少しずつでもいい
Even if it's just a little at a time,
私という答えを
we will find the answer that is "me"...
もっと
more...
もっと もっと
more and more!
夜空よ教えて 私の証は
Night sky, tell me, will the proof of my existence...
輝けるのかな
be able to shine?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I really want to find it!
誰かの決めたレールは
The rails decided by someone else
苦しくなるだけ
just make things painful.
ねぇ ノイズも力に変えるよ この心に誓う
Hey, I'll turn even the noise into strength. I swear it to my heart.
錆びついた運命の 歯車を回そう
Let's turn the gears of our rusted destiny.
ほら
See...
飾った感情は 脱ぎ捨てるから
because I'll cast off all decorated emotions.
そっと紡ぐシンフォニー
The softly spun symphony...
叶えたい願いを信じてる
believes in the wishes we want to fulfill.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょ
We have no choice but to sing with pride, right?
全力で
With all our might...
もっと もっと
more, more...
やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
until the day it finally turns into a song of hope...
もっと もっと
more, more...
悩みながらでいい 全てが宝物
It's okay to worry, everything is a treasure.
いつの日か この声を 受け取ってくれたなら
If someday you receive this voice of mine,
この言葉を君に もう大丈夫 ひとりじゃない
then these words are for you: "It's okay now, you are not alone."
強い想いを
These strong feelings...
繋ぐよ 一歩踏み出してみた
I will connect. I tried taking a step forward...
優しく世界は微笑む
and the world smiled gently.
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて
Leaving myself to my soaring emotions...
さあ行こう！
let's go!
響くカノネラ 新しい未来を感じてる
Resounding Kanonera, I feel a new future.
コンパクトにすすむしかないでしょ
We have no choice but to move forward compactly,
遠くまで
far away...
もっともっと届け この祈りよ 光となって
Send this prayer further and further, becoming light.
もっともっと 少しずつでもいい 私という答えを
More and more, even if it's little by little, the answer that is me...
もっと もっと もっと...
More, more, more...
雨とペトラ
[Title: Rain and Petra]
誰かが言った いつか空は 灰になって落ちるって
Someone said that someday the sky would turn to ash and fall.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
Consuming my days inside a world of delusions.
境界線を引いてしまうのも 共感覚のせいにして
Blaming synesthesia for having drawn a boundary line,
街の灯の海で 居場所を探している
I search for a place to belong in this sea of city lights.
どこへ行くにも この足は 退屈に染まって動かない
No matter where I go, these feet are stained with boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の景色が
The scenery just a little bit ahead,
見たいだけなのに 見たいだけなのに
even though I just want to see it, even though I just want to see it.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, it will surely drench my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered become so lovely to me...
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it will surely blur further away.
ふるさとなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has become my home.
誰かが言った いつか溜息は 夜に化けて歌を歌う
Someone said that someday a sigh will turn into the night and sing a song.
妄想の世の中で 日々を喰らっている
Consuming my days inside a world of delusions.
優しい嘘をなぞったせいで 離れる声に気付かない
Because I traced a gentle lie, I don't notice the voice growing distant.
溶けた月が足元に落ちて
The melted moon fell at my feet,
静かに揺れていた
swaying quietly.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったらきっと 今日を責めてしまう
If night falls, if night falls, I'm sure I'll blame today.
満たされない日々のそこで 夢を見ているだけ
Just dreaming at the bottom of these unfulfilled days.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしてもずっと 後悔と愛の隙間
Even if I look away, even if I look away, in the gap between regret and love...
取り残されてしまう前に 手を伸ばしてくれ
Before I get left behind, reach out your hand to me.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと
If it rains, if it rains, surely...
湿るアスファルト背に映して 俯いた
Reflecting on the damp asphalt behind me, I looked down.
一人ぼっちで ただ明日に期待をして
All alone, just holding expectations for tomorrow.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったらきっと 頬を濡らしてしまう
If it rains, if it rains, it will surely drench my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら 愛しくなるのに
Even the colors that have withered become so lovely to me...
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったらもっと 遠く霞んでしまう
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, it will surely blur further away.
ふるさとなった雨の音 笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh away the sound of the rain that has become my home.
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
Words I can believe, saying I want to stay connected,
だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば
because we already said goodbye to the us of yesterday.
青い春を過ごした 遠い稲妻
We spent our youth like a distant flash of lightning.
繋がっていたいって 信じられる言葉
"I want to stay connected" is a word I can believe in,
だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば
because we've already said goodbye to the us of yesterday.
青い春を過ごした
The blue spring we spent together...
遠い稲妻
...and the distant lightning.
切なく泣いて 前だけを向けたら
If only I could cry sadly and look ahead,
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろうな
I wonder how much easier things would have been.
この心を揺らした 一縷の望みは
This faint hope that shook my heart...
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
...I've stopped wishing for what I can't have. An incomplete human,
素晴らしき世界だけが
only this wonderful world...
答えを握ってる
...holds the answer.
諦めてしまうほど この先沢山の
Even to the point of giving up, so many...
後悔が君を待ってるけど
...regrets are waiting for you ahead, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
...no more, I won't get lost anymore!
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
To the point where I come to love these wounds too,
重ねてしまうよ
I'll keep overlapping them,
不格好なまんまでいいから
because it's okay to stay imperfect!
走れ その歩幅で
Run, at that pace!
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
Run, let your voice roar!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace both expectations and anxieties equally,
君と今を紡ぐ
spinning the present with you...
未来照らして
...and lighting up the future.
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't even know each other's faces or names,
たった1つの音をかき鳴らす
strum a single sound.
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A fleeting moment, like a prank, like a miracle,
あっという間に流れる時が
and time flows by in the blink of an eye.
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
The fear of continuing to remain as I am...
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
...we can't take back the lost time, but...
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ保存
If you only look back at the past...
泣いたっていいんだ
...it's okay to cry!
悔しさと痛みだけが
Because only frustration and pain...
君を肯定するから
...will affirm who you are.
大人になったら 忘れてしまうの保存
Will you forget it when you grow up?
君との約束をした場所は
The place where we made our promise...
もうない 覚えていたいよ
...is gone now, but I want to remember it.
思い出も愛しく 思えてしまうほど保存
To the point where I come to love these memories too,
重ねてしまうよ
I'll keep overlapping them,
不格好なまんまでいいから
because it's okay to stay imperfect.
その声はどこまでもなり響いて
Let that voice ring out forever,
確かな理由を抱いてここまで来たんだ
I've come this far holding onto a certain reason,
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
this is a journey that hasn't ended yet.
いつしか想いは形になる
Someday, our feelings will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる朝 忘れられないまま
Covered in this pure white morning, unable to forget,
だから
and so...
諦めてしまうほど
Even to the point of giving up, so many...
この先沢山の
...regrets are waiting for you ahead, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
...no more, I won't get lost anymore!
かけがえのないもの
Something irreplaceable...
溢れてしまうよ
...is overflowing.
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is right there in your hands,
離さないで
so don't let it go.
物語は一歩前へ
The story takes a step forward.
諦めてしまうほど
Even to the point of giving up, so many...
この先沢山の
...regrets are waiting for you ahead, but...
後悔が君を待ってるけど
...no more, I won't get lost anymore!
もうない 迷いはしないよ
To the point where I come to love these wounds too,
この傷も愛しく 思えてしまうほど
I'll keep overlapping them,
重ねてしまうよ
because it's okay to stay imperfect!
不格好なまんまでいいから
Run, at that pace!
走れ その歩幅で保存
Run, let your voice roar!
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
Embrace both expectations and anxieties equally,
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
spinning the present with you...
君と今を紡ぐ
...and lighting up the future.
未来照らして
六兆年と一夜物語
[Song: Six Trillion Years and an Overnight Story]
名も無い時代の集落の
In a village from a nameless era,
名も無い幼い少年の
there was a nameless, young boy.
誰も知らない おとぎばなし
A fairy tale that no one knows.
産まれた時から
From the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
as an unwanted child, an oni's child.
その身に余る
On this body,
罰を受けた
I received punishment beyond what I could bear.
悲しいことは
There's nothing sad
何も無いけど
about it, though.
夕焼け小焼け
With the glowing sunset,
手を引かれてさ
our hands are held.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything.
叱られた後の優しさも
Neither the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
nor the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当は 本当は寒いんだ
But the truth is, the truth is, the truth is, I'm cold.
死なない 死なない 僕はなんで死なない？
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢のひとつも見られないくせに
Even though I can't even dream a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎ話は
The fairy tale that no one knew,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was sucked into the sunset and disappeared.
吐き出すような暴力と
With violence that feels like it's being vomited out,
...さぁ打ち上げろ
...So let's set them off!
一発じゃ足りないのかい
Is one shot not enough?
二発目をおかわりしたい
Do you want a second helping?
三度目の正直なんて無い
There's no such thing as third time lucky,
四の五の言うなよ ロクでもない
stop making excuses, it's useless anyway.
茹だるような熱さが鬱陶しい
This sweltering heat is so annoying,
夜は薄着の天使が騒々しい
at night, the lightly-dressed angels are so noisy.
露出ばかり増えるんじゃ意味無いね
There's no point if it's just about showing skin,
本当の意味での祭りはこれからさ
the real festival is about to begin.
火傷するくらいの近距離で 仕込むスターマイン(スターマイン)
Setting up a star-mine at a burn-inducing close range.
今夜 あの空で合流して
Tonight, let's meet in that sky,
朝が満ちるまで それぞれの星も探そう Mommy...
and search for our respective stars until morning comes.
ねえ 今 同じこと思っていたんだって
Hey, you know, I was thinking the same thing just now,
ほら 話さなくても分かり合えた
see, we could understand each other without speaking.
あぁ あぁ こんな嬉しさをずっと
Ah, ah, I've always...
抱いてみたかった
...wanted to hold onto this kind of happiness.
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
The glowing future, the world we've been waiting for,
きらめいて目の前にあるから
are sparkling right before our eyes.
瞬きの刹那まで このストーリーの最後まで
Until the blink of an eye, until the very end of this story,
輝き放っていたいだ
I want to keep radiating light.
不完全な私達が 一瞬の欠片達が
Our imperfect selves, the fragments of a single moment,
重なって今ただ踊りだせたら
if we overlap and just start dancing now,
それは 夢見るだけじゃ叶わない想いを
these feelings that won't come true by just dreaming
ずっと新しくしていく
will keep becoming brand new.
ずっと 追いかけていこう
Let's keep chasing after them forever,
風を割いて
cutting through the wind,
雨を抜けて
passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ 満天の空へ
bloom proudly into the star-filled sky!
世界中のすべての人間に
To be liked by every single person
好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
in the world is just disgusting.
だけど一つになれない教室で
But in a classroom where we can't become one,
君と二人手を繋いでいたいの
I want to hold hands with you, just the two of us.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて
Raising a white flag to the violence of numbers,
悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
killing all bad feelings, say cheese!
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス
A sweet deep kiss of post-truth,
エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
erotically distorted love and peace.
自己中の光線銃乱射する
Rapidly firing ray guns of selfishness,
強者のナンセンス
the nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る殺しのライセンス
An haute couture license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
A game of musical chairs that created division,
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
a babe born from painless delivery.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
Calling a grand inside joke history.
生きたいが死ねと言われ_I want to live but they tell me to die.
I want to live, but they tell me to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ_I want to die but they tell me to live.
I want to die, but they tell me to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ_I want to live but they tell me to die.
I want to live, but they tell me to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ_I want to die but they tell me to live.
I want to die, but they tell me to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ？_Is boasting about happiness bad?
Is boasting about happiness bad?
不幸嘆いてもダメ？_Is lamenting misfortune bad?
Is lamenting misfortune bad?
図々しい言葉を避け_Avoiding cheeky words,
Avoiding cheeky words,
明るい未来のため_for a bright future,
for a bright future,
さんはい_One, two, three, go!
One, two, three, go!
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」_There are many people in this world who cannot even breathe.
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
さんはい_One, two, three, go!
One, two, three, go!
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」_There are many people in this world who cannot even breathe.
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てばこちらが立たず 譲り奪い守り行き違い_If this side stands, that side doesn't; giving, taking, protecting, passing by.
If this side stands, that side doesn't; giving, taking, protecting, passing by.
地雷原で立ち止まり 大人しく犬になるんだワン_Stopping in a minefield, meekly becoming a dog, woof!
Stopping in a minefield, meekly becoming a dog, woof!
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス・オブリージュ_Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige.
I love you_I love you.
I love you.
息苦しい日々の水面下_Below the surface of these suffocating days,
Below the surface of these suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花_A flower of blood wavers and smolders.
a flower of blood wavers and smolders.
ぼくらは コンプレックス コンプレックス コンプレックス_We are a complex, complex, complex...
We are a complex, complex, complex...
コンプレックスを武器に争う_...fighting using our complexes as weapons.
...fighting using our complexes as weapons.
それぞれの都合と自由のため_For our respective convenience and freedom,
For our respective convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを強制する_Forcing each other to hold our breath.
forcing each other to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる..._Suffocating, suffocating, suffocating...
Suffocating, suffocating, suffocating...
生きたいが死ねと言われ_I want to live but they tell me to die.
I want to live, but they tell me to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ_I want to die but they tell me to live.
I want to die, but they tell me to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ_I want to live but they tell me to die.
I want to live, but they tell me to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ_I want to die but they tell me to live.
I want to die, but they tell me to live.
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す_Wielding a chainsaw in "self-defense",
Wielding a chainsaw in "self-defense",
まともな人たちが怖いよ_The decent people terrify me.
the decent people terrify me.
愛燦燦 春爛漫 日々だんだん_Love shines bright, spring is in full bloom, day by day,
Love shines bright, spring is in full bloom, day by day,
大事なものが消えていくよ_Precious things are disappearing.
precious things are disappearing.
さんはい_One, two, three, go!
One, two, three, go!
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」_There are many people in this world who do not even know love.
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
さんはい_One, two, three, go!
One, two, three, go!
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」_There are many people in this world who do not even know love.
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 逆恨み 黒い涙がこぼれ落ち_Empathy, envy, jealousy, resentment, black tears spill over,
Empathy, envy, jealousy, resentment, black tears spill over,
醜い感情が吹き出し 真っ白い鳥になるんだな_Ugly emotions burst forth, and I turn into a pure white bird.
ugly emotions burst forth, and I turn into a pure white bird.
ノンブレス_Non-breath...
Non-breath...
息を止めることを
To hold my breath...
強制する
...is forced upon me.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
It's suffocating, it's suffocating, it's suffocating...
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める 息を止める
Hold your breath, hold your breath, hold your breath...
ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, Non-breath oblige!
I love you
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect each of our own loves,
君と防空壕で呼吸する保存
I breathe in a bomb shelter with you.
酸素が足りない...
I don't have enough oxygen...
酸素が足りないんですけど...
I don't have enough oxygen, but...
はい、はぁ...
Yeah... phew...
続けてやらせていただきました！
I went ahead and performed them back-to-back!
はい！いかがでしたでしょうか？
Yeah! How did you like them?
昨日の配信でも話したんですけど、
I also talked about this in yesterday's stream...
あの、一部人間じゃないやつがあるって言ってたのが、
that there is one part that isn't meant for humans to sing...
この「ノンブレス・オブリージュ」と、
and that was 'Non-breath oblige'...
先ほどね、ソロでやらせていただいた「毒チョコねえと一期一会物語」でした！
and 'Dokuchoko neeto Ichigoichie Monogatari' that I performed solo earlier!
はい！ちょっと、純粋に凄く心配だったんですけど、
Yes! Honestly, I was really worried...
なんとかね、できて良かったという、今はすごい...
but I'm so glad I somehow managed to pull it off...
安心で今、震えております。
Now, I'm literally shaking with relief.
はい！というわけでここまでたくさん見ていただきましたが、
Yes! So, you've watched quite a lot of performances so far...
皆さん、いかがですか？
everyone, how do you like it?
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって、
We had so many amazing guests come on,
AZKiちゃんと、あと、みお先輩、フレア先輩、ポルカ先輩、ねね先輩も！
AZKi-chan, Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, Polka-senpai, and Nene-senpai!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
本当にね、みんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きなやつを、
Really, for each song, I chose the ones I wanted to sing with them, the ones I love...
「この人にこれを歌ってるとこ聞きたい」っていう気持ちで選んで、一緒にやらせていただきました。
with the feeling of "I want to hear this person sing this song," and we got to perform them together!
本当にありがとうございます！先輩たちありがとう！
Thank you so much! Thank you, senpais!
はぁ、ちょっと、一回水飲んでいいか？水を飲ませてくれ！
Phew... can I drink some water? Let me drink some water!
よいしょ、はい。
There we go. Okay.
はい、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Alright, I've calmed down a bit.
はい、ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、次の曲に行きたいと思うんですけど、
Alright! So, we still have more to go, so I'd like to move on to the next song...
次の曲は、あの、昨日のトークでもめっちゃリクエストが上がってて、
For the next song, there were so many requests during yesterday's talk...
その前からずっとリクエストが上がってて、
and even before that, I've been constantly getting requests for it.
「あ、これ生誕ライブにやりたいな」ってことで、ずっと取っておいた曲です。
"Ah, I want to do this for my birthday live," so I saved this song for today.
なんで、楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
So, I hope you enjoy it! Now, please listen to the next song...
「ray」
"ray".
お別れしたのはもっと 前の事だったような
It feels like we parted ways much longer ago than we did.
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
I locked away that sorrowful light and wore down my heels.
君といた時は見えた
I could see it when I was with you.
今は見えなくなった
But now, it's out of sight.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
I'm vaguely searching for that transparent comet, yet that's all I look for.
しょっちゅう唄を歌ったよ
I sang songs all the time.
その時だけのメロディーを
Melodies meant only for those moments.
寂しくなんかなかったよ
I wasn't lonely at all.
ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
Because I was able to properly feel lonely.
いつまでどこまでなんて
Wondering how far and for how long...
正常か異常かなんて
...or whether things are normal or abnormal.
考える暇も無い程 歩くのは大変だ
It's so hard to walk, with no time to even think about it.
楽しい方がずっといいよ
It's much better to have fun.
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll keep hiding my pain with a smile.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
It's okay, that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
...won't fade away, even if I forget it.
理想で作った道を
The road paved with my ideals...
現実が塗り替えていくよ
...reality continues to paint over.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
On top of that path, those memories remain as a radiant shine.
お別れしたのは何で
Why did we part ways?
何のためだったんだろうな
What on earth was it all for?
悲しい光が
The sorrowful light...
悲しい光が僕の影を
The sad light stretches my shadow...
前に長く伸ばしている
...long before me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I get a fever.
時間がある時眠るよ
When I have time, I sleep.
夢だと解るその中で
In the midst of what I know to be a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll see you and then go again.
晴天とは程遠い
It is far from clear skies,
終わらない暗闇にも
even in the never-ending darkness.
星を思い浮かべたなら
If I think of stars,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I'll soon be in the galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
even if I get new shoes,
大丈夫だあの痛みは
it's alright, that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't disappear even if I forget.
伝えたかった事がきっと
There must have been something
あったんだろうな
I wanted to tell you.
恐らくありきたりなんだろうけど
It's probably a cliché, but
こんなにも
so much so...
お別れした事は
The goodbye we said
出会った事と繋がっている
is connected to our meeting.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet,
透明だから無くならない
won't disappear because it's transparent.
◯×△どれかなんて
Whether it's a circle, cross, or triangle,
皆と比べてどうかなんて
or how it compares to everyone else,
確かめる間も無いほど
there is not even time to confirm it,
生きるのは最高だ
living is the absolute best!
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I'll just fake it and keep smiling.
大丈夫だあの痛みは
It's alright, that pain
忘れたって消えやしない
won't disappear even if I forget.
大丈夫だこの光の
It's alright, at the beginning
始まりには君がいる
of this light, you are here.
はい！ということで
Yes! With that,
rayでしたー！
that was "ray"!
ああ、どうだったですか？
Ah, how was it?
めっちゃエモい...
It was so emotional...
エモい
...emotional...
感じになりましたね。
...kind of feeling.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Can I go drink some water for a second?
水、水が...
Water, where is the water...
うん。
Mm.
お。
Oh.
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水。いいだろう、風真いろは特注だぜ。
Water that doesn't run out no matter how much you drink. Great, isn't it? It's Kazama Iroha's special order.
よいしょ。ちょっと待って。
Here we go. Wait a second.
よし、はい。
Alright, okay.
というわけで、
And so,
次のね、曲にいきたいと思うんですけど、
I'd like to go to the next song, but...
あの昨日の配信でね、ちょっと匂わせをしたんですが、本日ですね、
Yesterday on stream I dropped a little hint, but today,
あの視聴者参加型3D生ライブになっておりまして、
this is actually a viewer-participation 3D live stream!
はい。
Yes.
今回はですね、皆様に投票をしていただいて次に歌う曲決めたいと思います。
This time, I'd like everyone to vote to decide the next song I will sing.
なんじゃそりゃって思うかもしれないんですけど、視聴者参加型、曲決め合戦っていうことで。
You might be wondering "What's that?", but it's a viewer-participation song choice battle!
それではテロップどうぞ！
So, please show the graphic on-screen!
ジャジャーン！
Ta-da!
えー、ANIMAか、ただ声一つ、どっちか！
Either "ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitotsu"!
で、投票が少なかった方もこのあとメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので、
The song with fewer votes will be sung during the members-only encore live,
よろしくお願いします！
so look forward to it!
いや、どちらも名曲で、迷いますよね。
Both are such great songs, it's hard to choose, right?
今、スタッフの人とどっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます。
Right now, I'm betting with the staff on which one it will be.
あの、どっちに賭けてるかは言わないんで。
I'm not telling you which one I bet on, though.
さあ、みんなこれで、次回の差し入れが豪華になるか裏で決まるからな。
So everyone, this will decide behind the scenes if my next catering will be fancy or not!
はい。ということで、
Yes. So,
早速、投票開始していきたいと思います！
I'd like to start the voting right away!
だいたい時間は1分くらいですかね。
The duration will be about 1 minute.
それでは、
Now then,
よーい...
ready...
スタート！
start!
届いた？
Did it reach you?
今、来たかな？
Did it come through just now?
お、たくさん来た来た来た、来た、来た、来た。
Oh, a lot of votes came in! They're coming in!
はい、じゃ、みんな投票ボタン押してね。
Alright, everyone, click the voting button.
じゃ、みんなが投票やってる間に、ゆっくりみんなのこと待つために帰るわ。メインステージ。
While you're voting, I'll slowly head back to wait for you. To the main stage!
じゃ、移動ですよ、移動！
So, time to move! Moving!
はい、というわけで、みなさん、投票した？
And with that, did everyone vote?
できてる？
Are you done?
どっちかだよ！
Choose one or the other!
両方はちょっとあれだから、どっちか、どっちかにお願いします。
Both is a bit much, so please pick one!
そういえば、今なんだかんだこうやって歩かせてもらってますが、
By the way, I'm walking around like this right now, but...
実はね、何気にね、ファーストミッション衣装がね、
Actually, surprisingly, this is my First Mission outfit...
見せるの？ゆっくり見せるのか？
Should I show it? Show it off slowly?
初めてお披露目するんだっけ？
Is this the first reveal?
そうだ、ここで、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。尺稼ぎじゃないよ！
Oh, right! Let me do some promotion here. Not to stretch for time!
宣伝ね！このあと、メン限でアフターライブがあるんですけど、
It's a promotion! We have an after-live for members later,
そのね、ときに、もっとこのカッコいいところをね、いっぱい見せますので、
and at that time, I'll show you much more of this cool side of me!
なんで是非よかったら、メン限のアフターライブにもお越しください！っていう宣伝も入れつつ、
So if you'd like, please come to the members-only after-live! Squeezing that promotion in...
みんな入れた？もう入れた？
Did everyone vote? Already done?
すごいや、これ、花道。長くない？長くない？
Wow, this runway is long. Isn't it long? Long, right?
これ、現地ライブでもやりたいな。
I'd love to do this at an in-person live too.
はい、だいぶカッコいい風真いろはをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが、
So I've been showing off a very cool Kazama Iroha,
いや、でもどっちかな？これ。
but I wonder which one it'll be.
「ANIMA」ね、みんな。設定の通りのあの、カッコいい！カッコいい！で。
With 'ANIMA,' it's cool and energetic, just as set up.
「ただ声一つ」はしっとり、しっとり、なんで、
While 'Tada Koe Hitotsu' is mellow and gentle,
これ、好みが分かれると思いますが、
so preferences will probably differ.
はい、いや、きっとね、どっちやってもみんなカッコいいって言ってくれるよね？
But surely, whichever it is, you'll say it's cool, right?
言ってくれるよね？
You'll say it, right?
言って、言ってくれる。あ、言ってくれる。
You will... Ah, you will!
カメラは言ってくれるということで。はい、というわけで、みんな、もう大丈夫かな？
The camera says you will! Alright, everyone, are you ready?
オッケー？
Okay?
じゃあ、そろそろ終わっちゃいますからね。はい、早く！早く投票してね！
I'm closing the vote soon. Quick, cast your votes now!
お、終わった。終わったんだよね？スタッフさん。
Oh, it's over. It's finished, right, staff?
終わった？
Is it done?
早かった？歩くの。
Did I walk too fast?
終わった？終わった、終わった、終わったかな？
Is it finished? Done, done? Is it done?
あ、なんか終わったらしい。今、賭けをしているスタッフと睨めっこしてます。
Ah, looks like it's over. I'm staring down the staff who placed bets.
それでは、結果発表タイム！
Now, it's time to announce the results!
ドゥルルルル...
Drumroll...
ジャジャン！
Tada!
アンケートの結果、ANIMAになったみたいです！
According to the poll, it's going to be ANIMA!
あ、これ、あの、賭けに勝った人の動きです。
Ah, this is the victory dance of someone who won the bet.
うぇーい！差し入れ期待してまーす！よっしゃー！
Yay! I'll be expecting treats! Yes!
というわけで、あの賭けにも勝ち、皆さんにも選んでいただき、とてもありがたい限りですね。
So, winning the bet and being chosen by everyone, I'm truly grateful.
あの、「ただ声一つ」の方も、このあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
I'll be singing 'Tada Koe Hitotsu' in the members-only stream later, so look forward to that!
というわけで、
And so...
早速歌っていきましょうか。
shall we get right to singing?
それでは聞いてください。「ANIMA」。
Please listen, 'ANIMA'.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What is the color of your soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"I'd rather just stay broken"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
Enough to throw it away, enough to run away,
強くないよ ほら
I'm not that strong, look...
もう一度
Once again,
鼓動高鳴る
my heartbeat races.
何が正しいかなんて
What is right or wrong,
わからないけど
I don't really know, but...
形のないものばかりが 大切になって行く
Only things without form become precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only the unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are tightly bound together.
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling and falling again, yet still unbroken.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What is the color of your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Simply getting hurt, acting tough, yet still wanting to find it,
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ防
I'm verifying the form of my soul.
...て
...ing
それぞれの道を行く
walking their own paths.
Find truth
寂しい思い出だけが
Only sad memories
強く根を張ってる
are firmly taking root.
まだ貫いて失って
Piercing again, losing,
それでも挫けない
even then I won't be discouraged.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて
Just left behind, slipping out,
それでも伝えたいよ
even then I want to convey it.
魂の日々を
The days of the soul,
魂の意志を
the will of the soul.
ずっと
Always...
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
...what color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
...what color is it?
透明な過去に
In the transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in the opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who are living,
何色ですか
what color are you?
また躓いて転がって
Stumbling again, rolling,
それでも砕けない
even then I won't break.
魂の色は
The color of the soul...
何色ですか
...what color is it?
ただ傷ついて強がって
Just getting hurt, putting up a front,
それでも見つけたいよ
even then I want to find it.
魂のカタチ
The shape of the soul,
確かめてるよ
I'm verifying it.
ずっと
Always...
はい、ということで
All right, and with that...
ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
I have performed "ANIMA"!
カロリー高い方だったなあ
That song burned a lot of calories!
お水、お水ください
Water, please give me some water.
カロリー高い方だった
That was a high-calorie one.
危ない
That was close.
ぷはー
Ah...
すいません
Excuse me.
あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すのを忘れていました
Um, I completely forgot to hand back the microphone.
やばい、音変になってなかったならいいな
Oh dear, I hope the sound didn't go weird.
すいません
I'm sorry.
ナチュラルに、スタッフさんがすっごい手を伸ばしてくれてたのに
The staff member was stretching their hand out so far,
疲れすぎてここ硬直してた
but I was so tired my body just froze up.
お水うまい
The water is so good!
減らないお水のおかげで、生きていけてます
Thanks to this magic bottomless water, I'm staying alive.
はい、じゃあちょっとこれ返して
Alright, let me return this...
はい
There we go.
それではですね、ちょっと、まだまだ続くんですけど
Now then, there's still more to come, but...
ここいらで一旦
...around here, let's take a moment...
重大告知タイムを
...for a major announcement time.
させていただきたいと思います！
I'd like to share some big news with you!
じゃあ、まずはいつものからいくか！
So, let's start with the usual one!
じゃあ、まずはこちら！
First, here's this!
風真いろは、誕生日記念グッズ2026出ます！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Commemorative Merchandise 2026 is coming out!
どんどこどんどこどんどこどん！
Dondoko dondoko dondoko don!
いやなんか良さそうなラインナップですねえ
My, that looks like a great lineup, doesn't it?
はい、今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで
Yes, we've put a lot of care into each item this time too,
皆さん楽しみにしていって欲しいです
so I hope you're all looking forward to them!
では、一つずつ、商品見ていきましょう！
Now, let's take a look at each product one by one!
まずはこちら！
First, this one!
タペストリーが出ます！
A tapestry is coming out!
タペストリー、実は、個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね
Actually, it's been a really long time since I released a tapestry as personal merchandise.
イラストは、もちぷよ先生描き下ろしで
The illustration is specially drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei,
雨上がりの青空の下で
...under a blue sky after the rain.
本当にね、このステージみたいな感じで
It really has the vibe of this stage,
あの、ライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで
...capturing the image of Kazama Iroha performing a live show.
描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for drawing this!
いや、めっちゃ良いよね、飾ってね！
It's so good! Please display it!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
フード付きタオル！
A hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです
Yes, it's a hooded towel featuring the same illustration as the tapestry.
フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております
The hood part is Pokobe's face, and it's detachable!
いや、なんか
You know,
こないだね、あの、ホロックスのライブあったじゃん
we had the holoX live concert the other day, right?
で、なんかダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど
My dance teacher told me this,
なんか風真いろは、異様にタオル購入率が良かったらしいなあ、お前たち
apparently, my fans had an incredibly high purchase rate for towels!
首にいっぱい巻いてくれて、偉いぞ！
You all wrapped them around your necks. Good job!
フード付きタオル...
The hooded towel...
これで擬似ポコべえごっこができるようになります
With this, you'll be able to play pretend Poko-bee!
擬似ポコべえごっこをしたい方、ま、取り外してね、そのまま飾りたい方もどうぞ
Those who want to pretend to be Poko-bee, or even those who just want to display it as is, go ahead!
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Yes, and next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
The plastic bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいのを作りました
Um, this is something I, Kazama Iroha, wanted, so we made it!
イラストはさめあんこ先生に描いていただきました
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei.
可愛いでしょう？この真ん中の穴に、ギュってペットボトルのところを入れて
Cute, isn't it? In this middle hole, you squeeze the neck of the bottle in...
使うやつです。はい、めっちゃおしゃれです
...to use it. Yes, it's very stylish!
よかったら使ってください。カバンとかつけて持ち運べるんでね
Please use it if you like. You can attach it to your bag to carry it around!
はい。そしてラストはこちら！
Yes, and lastly, this one!
はい。実は地味になかった
Yes! It actually didn't exist until now...
セーラー服版の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ！なんと、ボイス付きです！
...the sailor-uniform version of Kazama Iroha's plushie! And it comes with voice recordings!
こちらも、さめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました
This design was also thought up by Sameanko-sensei.
レインポンチョを着た、声が出るぬいぐるみです
It's a vocal plushie wearing a rain poncho.
お腹をにぎりしめると、音が出るらしいぞ
Squeezing its tummy apparently makes a sound.
今のところはな、はい
At least, for now! Yes.
外出時にカバンなどにつけることもできますって
It says you can also attach it to your bag when going out.
ボイスなんですけど、天気に関するものをとったんですよ
As for the voices, I recorded ones related to the weather.
どんな感じかはまだ、さすがに言えないけど、だけど...
I can't say how they sound just yet, but...
おみくじ感覚で聞いて、その天気にならなかったからといって風真いろはを責めないでください
Please listen to it like a fortune slip. Don't blame Kazama Iroha if the weather doesn't match!
自己責任で、にぎにぎしてください
Please squeeze it at your own risk.
買ってからのお楽しみです
Look forward to it after you buy it!
いっぱいありましたが、フルセット見ていきましょう！
We have quite a lot, so let's look at the full set!
こちら！
This is it!
今回のグッズはセーラーのイメージに合わせて、フェス風をテーマに作ってみました
The merchandise this time is themed around a festival style to match the sailor uniform.
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで、よかったらよろしくお願いします
They are highly practical and perfect for the coming season, so please consider getting them!
そして、フルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is... this!
数量限定版あります
There is a limited quantity version available.
風真いろはの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード。ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね
A ticket-style card with Kazama Iroha's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped duplicated message. It's quite stylish!
そして、通常版には、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます
And the regular version comes with a ticket-style card featuring a foil-stamped duplicated signature and message.
さらに、どちらにも、あの、ボイスがついてきますね、はい
Furthermore, both of them come with a voice recording. Yes!
「君と雨宿り」というタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど
It comes with a voice recording titled "Sheltering from the Rain with You."
まあぶっちゃけ、気になったら聞いてください
Well, to be honest, please listen to it if you're curious!
ボイスは、めちゃ、気合入れて撮ったからね！
I really put my heart and soul into recording that voice!
はい、ということで、まあシチュエーションボイスですね。雨宿り系だった気が、なんか、照れながら撮った気がします
So it's a situation voice. I think it was "sheltering from the rain" style, and I remember recording it while feeling quite embarrassed.
そしてグッズは21時カートオープンです
And the merchandise cart opens at 21:00!
すみません、生配信につき、ちょっと、時間が押しそうなんですけど
I'm sorry, because this is a live stream, we might be running a bit behind schedule...
ゆっくり買ってね、とは言えず、頑張ってください！
...so I can't tell you to take your time buying. Please do your best!
どうしよう、フォローのしようがない、ごめん
What should I do? There's no way to cover for that. Sorry!
そして、21時からホロメンの多分配信が控えてると思うんですけど、何も気にしなくていいんでスタートしてくださいね
And, um, from 21:00, other Hololive members probably have streams scheduled, but please don't worry about me and just start!
はい。そして、まだまだあります、まだまだ。それがこちら！
Yes. And there's still more, still more! And that is... this!
はい。新曲！いえい！
Yes, a new song! Yay!
風真いろは、新曲が出ます
Kazama Iroha is releasing a new song!
タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」。作詞作曲は「いろはステップ」でもおなじみ、40mPさんにしていただきました！
The title is "Kazamuki Entropy." It was written and composed by 40mP-san, who is also well-known for "Iroha Step"!
配信後にこちらMVが公開されます
The MV for this song will be released after this stream.
多分こっそり今、マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず
I think my manager is secretly switching it to a premiere release right now.
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The song itself will be released at midnight!
そして、ジャケットの文字は、風真いろはさんが自分で書きました。はい。ありがとうございます
Also, the text on the jacket cover was handwritten by Kazama Iroha herself. Yes, thank you!
ということで、もう終わっちゃうんですけど、トレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました。くそ！
So, we are already reaching the end, but I just received word that we're trending at number two! Damn!
あと残り、頑張ってくれと言いたいけど、みんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとうね
I want to say "keep it up until the end," but everyone, thank you so much for posting so much!
よし、じゃあ準備できた？大人の準備が全部できてそうなので
Alright, are you ready? It seems the staff are all ready...
早速、新曲、歌っていきたいと思います！
...so without further ado, I'd like to perform the new song!
しかし、今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました！
However, I've prepared something a bit special for this time!
ゴンドラ、来い！
Gondola, come on out!
おお！リハーサルで見たけどやっぱりいいな、これ
Oh! I saw it during rehearsal, but this is really great!
ほい
Hop!
というわけで、みんなポコべえがいなくて寂しかったでしょ？
So, you all missed Poko-bee, didn't you?
今年はゴンドラになりました！
This year, he has become a gondola!
はい、というわけで、早速やっていくんですが
Yes, so I'll get right to it, but...
ドア、オープン！
...door, open!
いえい、ほっ。乗っちゃおうね
Yay, hop! Let's get on.
というわけで、早速歌っていきたいと思います
So, without further ado, I'd like to sing.
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは新オリジナル曲「風向きエントロピー」
Please listen to Kazama Iroha's new original song, "Kazamuki Entropy."
ねえ いつからそこにあったの
Hey, since when has it been there?
あまりにも近すぎて 気づかなかったよ
It was so close that I didn't even notice.
ずっと 私が生まれた日から
Ever since the day I was born,
そばにいてくれたのにね
You've always been by my side, and yet...
曖昧で
Ambiguous,
複雑で
complex,
予測不可能で
and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わっていく 空の模様
the pattern of the sky constantly changing on a whim.
その精一杯じゃ うまく笑えない
With just that level of effort, I can't smile well,
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
世界は優しくて
the world is kind.
いつか風が生まれた
Someday the wind was born,
足跡が始まる場所
the place where footprints begin.
あの日の荷物抱えて
Carrying that day's baggage,
駆け出したとしても ここに来るんだろう
even if I run out, I'll probably end up here.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, and this voice too,
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors me.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I don't know which way to go yet, but
ただ風の吹くままに
I'll just blow with the wind.
ねぇ いつから気づいていたの
Hey, when did you start to notice?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
It's as if you can see right through me.
苦し紛れにごまかした嘘も
Even the desperate lies I made up,
君にはバレていたのかな
I wonder if you saw through them all.
平凡で 退屈で あくび混じりで
Ordinary, boring, and filled with yawns,
変哲のない ありふれてる時間
this is just an ordinary, common time.
想像しただけじゃ何も変わらない
Just imagining things won't change a thing.
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
予測してた以上に ほら
look, even more than I predicted...
新しい風が吹き抜けていって
A new wind starts to blow through,
不器用な自分がやけに愛しく思えたんだ
making my clumsy self seem strangely endearing.
いつか風が止んで
Someday when the wind stops,
足跡が途切れた場所
and the footprints fade away,
落とし物探して 拾って
I'll search for what was lost, pick it up,
見つけ出せたから ここにいるんだろう
and because I found it, I must be here.
そっと 髪がなびく
Gently, my hair flutters.
いつか風が夢見た
Someday the wind dreamed of
青空と交わる場所
the place where it meets the blue sky.
回り道選んで 迷って 躓いたとしても
Even if I take detours, get lost, and stumble,
そこへ行くんだろう
I'll still make my way there.
この景色も この声も
This scenery, and this voice too,
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors me.
等身大の手で握りしめて
Holding tight with my true, down-to-earth hands.
想像以上にもっと自由な速度で
At a speed more free than I ever imagined.
方向なんてまだわからないけど
I don't know which way to go yet, but
ただ風 of 吹くままに
I'll just blow with the wind.
はい！というわけで、ありがとうございました！
Alright! And with that, thank you very much!
よいしょ。みんな、すっかり忘れてると思うけど...
Oof. I think everyone has completely forgotten, but...
今日、これから記念撮影します！
we are going to take a commemorative photo now!
そう、お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
That's right, I told you there would be souvenirs, right?
これ、これ。いや、ちょっと待って。マジで自撮り棒...
This, this. Wait a second, seriously, this selfie stick...
これ、リハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに...
I practiced this so much during rehearsals...
自撮り棒下手。
but I'm so bad at using a selfie stick.
あ、いい感じいい感じ。
Ah, this looks good, looks good.
カシャッ。
Click.
よし、いけてそういけてそう。
Okay, looks like it worked, looks like it worked.
おっけー。
Okay!
はい、というわけで、皆さん。今日「お土産あり」って言いましたね？
So, everyone. I did say there would be souvenirs today, right?
そうなんです。
That's right!
今日撮った、今この風真がね、自撮り棒で撮った写真が...
The photo that I, Kazama, just took with the selfie stick...
コンビニで、なんとプリントアウトできます！
can actually be printed out at convenience stores!
すごーい！
Amazing!
はい、こちらですね、対象店舗ファミリーマートさん、ローソンさん、ミニストップさんで
Yes, this is available at FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop,
本日21時から、ネットで事前購入ができます！
and you can purchase it online in advance starting today at 9:00 PM!
お値段がですね、税込み300円とのことで、
The price is 300 yen (including tax),
印刷できるのは、明日の6月19日、20時までになっております。
and you can print it until tomorrow, June 19th, at 8:00 PM.
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、あの、この後書きますんで。
On the photo, I'll be writing a printed handwritten message after this.
どんな写真が撮れているか、ちょっと写真下手くそでも怒らないでね？
As for what kind of photo we got, please don't be mad if my photography skills are bad!
内容は買ってから確認してください！
Please check the photo after you buy it!
いや、すごいよね。ちょっといち早く皆さんのもとに、手元に残るライブのお土産が用意できればということで、
It's amazing, isn't it? I wanted to get a physical souvenir from the live show to you as quickly as possible,
今回やらせていただきました。お土産あります！
so that's why we did this. We have souvenirs!
ちょっと皆さん 各自で回収って形で それだけが申し訳ないんですが
I'm sorry you have to go collect it yourselves, but...
お土産ありますんで
I have a souvenir for you!
ぜひ気になったら コンビニでプリントしてみてください！
So if you're interested, please try printing it at a convenience store!
そして コンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日 17時59分までです
Also, the convenience store prints are available until July 21st at 5:59 PM!
概要欄に写真購入のリンク 多分今マネちゃんがやってくれていると思いますので よろしくお願いします！
I think my manager is setting up the link to buy the photos in the description right now, so please check it out!
そしてこの後はですね MVの公開と
And after this, we have the MV release,
メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので
and the membership-exclusive encore live,
そちらも絶対聞きに来てくださいね！
so you absolutely must come listen to that too!
それでは皆さん またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, let's meet again!
最高の誕生日でした！
It was the best birthday ever!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!